Diego Favero Full Stack Developer

Online Resume and Code Samples: http://18.216.194.20/diegofavero.dev/

GitHub: https://github.com/orisha

StackOverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/688689/diego-favero

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/faverodiego/

Brazilian, Born at: 16th, May, 1981 E-mail: diego.g.favero@gmail.com Phone: +55 75 998123412

Common Used Tools

#PHP #MYSQL #GOLANG

#UI UX #LINUX #JAVASCRIPT

#SYMFONY #KOTLIN #DOCKER

About me:

I have been using **PHP** and its 'sidekicks' for web development since **1999** when I started to be an intern in the university's computer's lab.

Today I am able to work in any stage from a system development:

Since analyze system requirements, going thru server setup, database design and administration, team managing, coding (Structure, **Backend** and Frontend), test and deployment!

Currently, I have based my projects on **microservice** architecture. Using **Golang** as BackEnd.

I am really up to start to learn new technologies.

Today, I consider myself better fit as backend **developer** than frontend.

I Have a good knowledge about Photography, Video Editing and Audio Production, able to use many softwares such as Adobe suite, Logic Pro, Ableton Live and many others.

I have been DJing since 2007.

As a hobby I like outdoor sports such as rock climbing, trekking and mountain bike, and sometimes, I make awesome woodwork! (Most of my house's furniture are made by me).

Technical Skills

Level 8 (I would be able to perform a workshop of these right now)

PHP OOP Mysql

Level 7 (I can work very well using these, with some kind of expertise)

Javascript Jquery Symfony PHPStorm (IDE) OSX Linux

Level 6 (I Can do it! Maybe I'll use google to check any syntax or a forgotten detail)

GoLang API Apache
Mysql Server Git AWS
SOAP/REST SEO DBA

Level 5 (I can do it! I have already used it! Just give a few days on google)

Kotlin Docker TDD

XML Python Design Patterns

Node.js Angular React

Vue .js Nginx SSL / HTTPS

Level 4 (tools I already used, but not that much, so I am able to use it)

ExtJS Kendo UI Codelgniter CSS3 SASS/LESS HTML5

Level 3 (I know what is and how to apply, but never worked using those before)

Ruby NoSql WordPress Bootstrap Pearl Kubernetes

Level 2 (Languages I learned in college, but never used professionally)

C, C++ Java Pascal Cobol Lua Delphi Assemble Fortran ASP

Education:

Title: Bachelor

Course : Information Systems Bachelor's Degree at **UNESP** (Sao Paulo State University)

from March 1999 until December 2003

The Course, basically, is a shortened form of Science Computers **plus** company management course. In short words: **It teaches how to apply computers based systems for companies**.

* Original title in portuguese : Bacharelado em Sistemas de Informação.

** The <u>Information Systems Bachelor</u> at UNESP it is the first course of its kind in Brazil. And since them it has been always ranked as #1 in Brazil.

***The Sao Paulo State University is into top 4 Brazilian Ranking and it is in top 400 world wide.

Languages Skills

Portuguese (pt-BR): native speaker.

English: Advanced

I (really) learned English when was **living** in Amsterdam (2008-2009), today I could say that I am aware of my strong Brazilian accent, also a few mess when need to use 'in', 'on', 'at', etc, although, I think I can **express** myself clearly enough to hold any kind of conversation, written or **spoken**.

Spanish: Intermediary

Due to its **similarity** to portuguese, I can understand spanish very well when spoken and fully when read . But I can not speak as good as I speak English

French/Italian: Self Learning

Like Spanish, these other **latin** languages are kind of easy to understand, but I still don't get much of it when spoken. I just need a bit more practice.

Work Experience

NetSar Senior PHP Programmer nov 2012 — Jul 2014

Brazilian Based Company - Home Office

It is a medium software company in Brazil providing **solutions** for travel shop's. It was home based job. I was **leading** a small team (me plus 2 programmers, occasionally a designer) responsible for re-write the old scripts into a new **Symfony** based platform. Eventually, I did write codes for new features. Most of the system was based on **SOAP/REST** servers!

Reason for getting off: In may 2014 I had a motorcycle crash, which costs me three broken ribs and a pierced lung, a week in the hospital and almost cost my life. After that I decided to give myself some time so I asked to get off for travel.

<u>Advosoft</u> PHP Developer Jun 2012 — Oct 2012 USA Based company. - Home Office

It was home based job. I was simply coding new **features** according to the projects previous sent thru some collab tool .

Reason to getting off: They let me go without further explanation.

<u>Ecentry</u> Jr PHP Developer - Jan 2010 — Dec 2011 Brazil Based Company - Office Based Job

I Was working on a Fidelity Program System owned by **Lufthansa** Flight Company. This system responsible for managing the Fidelity Points Program for the ones who sells Lufthansa tickets. It was a huge system within almost **2M** users, translated into more than 80 **languages**.

I had two main functions:

- 1 Maintenance: Had to quickly fix any reported bug.
- 2 New Interface and Database **Optimization**: While no bugs were reported, I had a mission to check and optimize the **SQL's** query and system performance. To do so, I was migrating all queries to be executed by **Python** Scripts.

The new interface was developed using **ExtJS** Framework.

Reason to getting off: I was sick to have to spend two hours every day into the Brazilian mad traffic. After been denied to work home based, I asked to guit!

My Goals

_ MultiTask and vast tech knowledge : I can fit in many positions into IT department.
_ Can travel or move in anytime .
_ Dare me on new challenges !
_ I think 'out the box' and love to learn.
_ I can inject new market vision ('cause I live the Brazilian reality, would be a nice info and
experiences exchange about this huge and growing marketing we have around here).

Interests

Augmented Reality UI / UX New Technologies

Qubits Data Security Networks

Big Data Machine Learning IA

Interests beyond IT

A few things I like to do and learn about in my spare time :

- _ Photo / Video / Audio Production and Edition
- _ Sports -> Climbing, Mountain bike, Surf, SlackLine and Trekking.
- _ Healthier life and food .
- _ Travel
- _ Quantum physics.
- _ Yoga and Capoeira .
- _ Politics and Economy .
- _ Dogs .
- _ Simple Life .
- _ Carpenter and Architecture .

Why to hire me?

Because I have a fully **domain** about how to attend the job needs (if hooded by my **skills**, otherwise, I am fully open to learn it) with a few pluses acquired by life experience. And, I have a passion for work with **technologies**!

Please, take a look on my <u>Cover Letter</u> to know a bit more about me .